PERSONAL DETAILS



Reading, Berkshire, UK



(+44) 7935099111



sachinidissanayaka269@gmail.com



Sachini-Dissanayaka.github.io



linkedin.com/in/sachini-dissanayaka



github.com/Sachini-Dissanayaka

TECHNICAL EXPOSURE

Programming Languages

Java, Python, Javascript, Dart

Full-stack Development

Angular, React.js, Node.js, Flask, SpringBoot, MongoDB, MySQL

Mobile Development

Java, Android SDK, Flutter

Cloud Technologies

Firebase, Google Cloud Platform

Machine Learning

Jupyter notebook, NumPy, Pandas, Scikitlearn, PyTorch, BeautifulSoup Tensorflow, Matplotlib

Other

Git, Bitbucket, Jira, Postman, Apache Tomcat, Maven, Elasticsearch

ACHIEVEMENTS

IEEE Xtreme 2021

Country Rank - 18

MoraXtreme 6.0

Rank - 15

IEEE YESIST12: Hackathon

Ranked 4th in the Preliminary Selection Competition Sri Lanka 2019 and got selected for the finals in Stamford University in **Thailand**

HomeAlone: Virtual Mini-Hackathon

Island Rank - 15

HackDown 2020 - Coding Competition

Island Rank - 19

IEEEXtreme 2019

Country Rank - 57

SACHINI DISSANAYAKA

SUMMARY

I'm a passionate programmer who has around 2 years of experience in developing software. My interests lie in NLP, Competitive Programming, System Design, Software Security, and Data Science. Currently, I'm looking for a great team to find my next adventure as a Software Engineer.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - HighFlyer

May 2023 - Present

React, Typescript

HighFlyer is a UK based firm that offers a comprehensive range of services for organizations

- Developed an analytics portal using React.js and Recharts which users can select filters and view the analytics in various chart types, such as line charts, bar charts, pie charts, and more.
- Implemented additional functionalities like drag and drop, full screen view, clipboard copying and pdf generation from the dashboard items.
- This allowed me to strengthen my skills in frontend development, data visualization, and user interface design.

Software Engineer - WSO2 Inc

May 2022 - Jan 2023

Java, Maven

WSO2 is an open-source technology provider in the API Management domain

- Responsible for migrating the Twilio SDK version from 3.3.13 to 8.36.0 in the Twilio ESB Connector.
- Worked on integration tests in service catalog which is a component of the API
- Implemented server restarts tests for APIM versions 4.0.0, 4.1.0, and 4.2.0 to mitigate regression issues.

Software Engineer - Emojot (Pvt) Ltd - (Internship) Oct 2020 - May 2021

JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB

Emojot is a global pioneer in real-time emotion-based intelligent experience management

- Contributed to the system security enhancement by implementing a multifactor authentication system for Emojot Dashboard and Customer Experience Management Portal (CX Portal) which were the main client-facing applications.
- Improved the existing user operations and setup user authorization levels to monitor user engagement with the platform.

EDUCATION

BSc Engineering (Honours)

2018 - 2022

2008 - 2016

Specialised in Computer Science & Engineering University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Overall GPA 3.62 (Second class upper division)

G.C.E Advanced Level Examination ACC, Sri Lanka

Distinction passes with 3A's for all 3 subjects Combined Mathematics, Physics, and Chemistry District Rank - 01 | Z-Score - 2.3770

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Batch Representative

Department of Computer Science & Engineering, University of Moratuwa 2021 - 2022

IT Panelist and Executive Member

UoM Leo Club, University of Moratuwa 2020 - 2021

Article Writer

MoraSpirit, University of Moratuwa 2019 - 2021

Volunteer and Organiser

UoM Leo Club, University of Moratuwa Chairman - "Mini-Miracles project 2019" 2019 - 2021

School Senior Prefect

Pu/Anamaduwa Central College 2014 - 2016

School Junior Prefect

Pu/Anamaduwa Central College 2010- 2013

ARTICLES

Implementation of Two-Factor
Authentication with TOTP using
Speakeasy

<u>Article Link</u>

Integration of Huawei Account Kit (In Kritify Application)

Article Link

PROJECTS & RESEARCHES

<u>Invity</u> <u>Website</u>

(React.js, Node.js, Firebase)

This is an automated bulk invitation generator. Users can upload an image file of an invitation, and then use the in-built tools to customize the invitation as they prefer. The magic of the platform is that it lets users to generate a set of invitations with multiple addressees just by a single click.

Hybrid-Attention End-to-End Speaker Diarization University Final Year Research

(Deep Learning, PyTorch, Python, GCP)

This is based on the implementation of the state-of-the-art model for 2 speaker overlapping speech diarization by reducing the diarization Error Rate (DER). We proposed three more models by improving the current state-of-the-art Self Attention model, which are the combinations of the Local Dense Synthesizer-Attention layer with Self Attention, Relative Attention, and External Attention layers.

Search Engine Politicians - Sinhala

Source Code

(Python, Flask, React.js, BeautifulSoup, Elasticsearch, Kibana)

This is an information retrieval system that can be used to query and get any type of data about Sinhala Politicians. The dataset of the project was scrapped using BeautifulSoup and the project was implemented using Python, React.js, and supported by a python-Flask powered backend. I have used Elasticsearch for indexing and querying.

Distributed Chat System

Source Code

(Java, Gradle)

This is a distributed chat application that supports multiple chat rooms. The system consists of two main distributed components: chat servers and chat clients. They can independently run on different hosts and elect a leader to handle operations using the Leader election algorithm. I implemented all the server API functions to accept CRUD operations and implemented the Heartbeat algorithm using gossiping and consensus for failure detection.

DrivenData | Pump-It-Up

Source Code

(Python, Jupyter Notebook)

This is a Python solution for the Pump-It-Up, DrivenData machine learning competition. I was able to place within the top 4% of the global participant results in this competition.

Kritify Source Code

(Android Studio, Java, Spring Boot)

This is a social media mobile app that hosts all your reviews about business entities in one place. This is an Android app integrated with HMS core. I have implemented the functionalities for Huawei Account Kit, post creation, and a point-based reviewing system for each visited place.

TravelME Source Code

(Flutter, Dart)

This is an "Online tour planning platform" that can be used for planning a tour and the mobile application frontend was implemented from scratch using Flutter.